jvpschoolofmysticalarts.com 2018-06-24

# Privacy Policy - JVP School of Mystical Arts

Your privacy is important to **One Light Productions, Inc.** ,  
[www.VanPraagh.com](http://www.vanpraagh.com/), and [JVPSchoolofMysticalArts.com](https://www.jvpschoolofmysticalarts.com/) so we’ve  
developed a Privacy Policy that covers how we collect, use, disclose,  
transfer, and store your information. We know that you care how  
information about you is used and shared, and we appreciate your trust  
that we will do so carefully and sensibly. This notice describes our Privacy  
Policy on this site. Please take a moment to familiarize yourself with our  
policy practices and feel free to contact us if you have any further  
questions.

**IMPORTANT: By visiting[www.VanPraagh.com](http://www.vanpraagh.com/) and/or  
[www.JVPSchoolofMysticalArts.com](https://www.jvpschoolofmysticalarts.com/), you are accepting all of the  
practices described in this Privacy Notice, and any dispute over  
privacy is subject to this notice of privacy and our conditions of use,  
including limitations on damages, resolutions of disputes and  
applications of the laws of the State of California.**

Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Notice applies to all  
information that we have about you and your account. We may e-mail  
periodic reminders of our notices and conditions, but even if we don’t, you  
should check our Web site frequently to see recent changes which will  
control retroactively even if we do not notify you of those changes. We  
stand behind the promises we make. If you have concern about privacy at  
[www.VanPraagh.com](http://www.vanpraagh.com/) and/or [www.JVPSchoolofMysticalArts.com](https://www.jvpschoolofmysticalarts.com/), please  
contact us with a complete description and we will try and resolve it to your  
satisfaction.

**Last updated: April 1, 2015.**

 **Collection and use of personal information: What personal  
information do we collect?**

Personal information is data that can be used to identify or contact a single  
person due to your unique information. We collect information from you  
when you register on our site, subscribe to our newsletter, register for a  
course, purchase materials or fill out a form.

When ordering or registering on our site, or when you contact us, as  
appropriate, you may be asked to provide personal information and to enter  
such information such as your: name, e-mail address, mailing address and/  
or phone number, contact preferences and credit card information, etc. You  
may, however, visit our site anonymously and you can choose not to  
provide us with any of that information, but if that’s the case, you might not  
be able to take advantage of our many features.

We may store and share this personal information with those in this  
company or with its affiliated companies, and use it consistent with this  
Privacy Policy. These companies may also combine it with other  
information they have gathered in order to provide and improve their  
products, services, content and advertising. If you choose to provide us  
with contact information such as the above for friends or family, we may  
collect and use that information as well.

**What do we use your information for?**

The personal information we collect from you allows us to keep you posted  
on many features of our site, such as our latest announcements, updates  
and upcoming events, courses, literature, books and products, for example.  
We also use personal information to help us develop, deliver and improve  
our products or materials, services, content and advertising. Any of the  
information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:

  1. To personalize your experience:  
Your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs;
  2. To improve our website:  
We continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the  
information and feedback we receive from you;
  3. To process transactions:  
Your information, whether public or private, will not be sold,  
exchanged, transferred, or given to any other company for any reason  
whatsoever, without your consent, other than for the express purpose of  
delivering the purchased product or a service you have requested;
  4. To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature;
  5. To send periodic emails:  
The email address you provide for order processing or registering,  
may be used to send you information and updates pertaining to your order  
or registration, in addition to receiving occasional company news, updates,  
important notices, related product or service information, changes in our  
terms or policies which will be effective retroactively without further notice  
to you, etc.; and,
  6. We may use personal information for internal purposes such as  
auditing, data analysis, and research to improve ourselves and what we  
provide to you.

**Please Note:** If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving  
future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of  
each email.

**Collection and use of Non-personal information: What information do  
we collect?**

We also collect non-personal information that is data in a form that does  
not permit direct association with any specific person or individual. We  
may collect, use, transfer, and disclose non-personal information for any  
purpose. The following are some examples of what we collect and how we  
might use it:

  1. We may collect information such as your occupation, language, zip  
code, area code, unique device identifier, location, etc. so that we can  
better appreciate you and perhaps provide or improve products, services,  
announcements and advertising; and,
  2. We may also collect information about your activities on this website,  
and this information will be used to help us provide you with more useful  
information, as well as understand which parts of our website, products and  
services are of most interest to people like you. We call this “aggregated  
data” and it is considered non-personal information for the purposes of this  
Privacy Policy. Of course, if we do combine this “non-personal information”  
with “personal information” the combined information will be treated as  
personal information for the duration that it is combined.

**Automatic Information**

Examples of the information we collect and analyze include the Internet  
protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet; login;  
e-mail address; password for this site; computer and connection  
information such as browser type, version, and time zone setting, browser  
plug-in types and versions, operating system, and platform; purchase  
history, which we sometimes aggregate with similar information from other  
customers; the full Uniform Resource Locator (URL) clickstream to,  
through, and from our Web site, including date and time; cookie number  
(see below for more explanation about “cookies”); and products you viewed  
or searched for. During some visits we may use software tools such as  
JavaScript to measure and collect session information, including page  
response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page  
interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and  
methods used to browse away from the page. We may also collect  
technical information to help us identify your device for fraud prevention  
and diagnostic purposes.

**How do we protect your information?**

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety and  
security of your personal information when you enter, submit, or access  
your personal information.

We offer the use of a secure server. All supplied sensitive/credit information  
that you may offer to us is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL)  
technology and then encrypted into our Database to be only accessed by  
those authorized with special access rights to our systems, and are  
required to keep the information confidential.

After a transaction, your private information (credit cards, social security  
numbers, financials, etc.) will not be kept on file for more than sixty (60)  
days. If and when we request credit card for orders, we will reveal only the  
last four digits of your credit card numbers when confirming an order. Of  
course, we transmit the entire credit card number to the appropriate credit  
card company during order processing, and you agree to allow us to do so.  
If you do give us your credit card information, it is important for you to  
protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your  
computer. Be sure to sign off or log off when finished using a shared  
computer. 

**“Cookies and Other Technologies–What are “cookies” and do we use  
cookies?**

We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact  
with us. For example, like many Web sites, we use “cookies.” Cookies are  
small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s  
hard drive through your Web browser (if you so allow) that enables the  
sites or service providers systems to recognize your browser and capture  
and remember certain information. We use them and other technologies  
you may have heard of such as “Pixel Tags” and “Web Beacons.”

We use cookies and such other technologies to better understand your  
behavior, tell us which part of the website you have visited and to save your  
preferences for future visits and compile aggregate data about site traffic  
and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in  
the future. We may contract with third-party service providers to assist us in  
better understanding our site visitors. These service providers are not  
permitted to use the information collected on our behalf except to help us  
conduct and improve our business.

We treat information collected by cookies and other technologies as nonpersonal  
information. However, to the extent that Internet Protocol (IP)  
addresses or similar identifiers are considered personal information by local  
law, we also treat these identifiers as personal information. Similarly, to the  
extent that non-personal information is combined with personal information,  
we treat the combined information as personal information for the purposes  
of this Privacy Policy.

We might use cookies and other technologies in mobile advertising  
services to control the number of times you see a given ad, deliver ads that  
relate to your interests, and measure the effectiveness of ad campaigns.

If you want to disable cookies and you’re using the Safari web browser, go  
to Safari preferences and then to the Security pane to disable cookies. On  
your mobile device, go to Settings, then Safari, and then to the Cookies  
section. The Help feature on most other browsers will tell you how to  
prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the  
browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable  
cookies altogether. Additionally, you can disable or delete similar data used  
by browser add-ons, such as Flash cookies, by changing the add-on’s  
settings or visiting the Web site of its manufacturer. For other browsers,  
check with your provider to find out how to disable cookies. Please note  
that certain features of this website may not be available once cookies are  
disabled. Because cookies allow you to take advantage of some of our  
essential features, we recommend that you leave them turned on, but the  
choice is entirely up to you.

As is true of most websites, we gather some information automatically and  
store it in log files. This information may include but not be limited to  
Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser type and language, Internet  
service provider (ISP), referring and exit pages, operating system, date/  
time stamp, and clickstream data.

We use this information to understand and analyze trends, to administer  
the site, to learn about user behavior on the site, and to gather  
demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may also  
use this information in our marketing and advertising services.  
In some of our email messages, we might use a “click-through URL” linked  
to content on our website. When you click one of these URLs, you will pass  
through a separate web server before arriving at the destination page on  
our website. We track this click-through data to help us determine interest  
in particular topics and measure the effectiveness of our communications  
with you. If you prefer not to be tracked in this way, you should not click text  
or graphic links in the email messages.

Pixel tags enable us to send email messages in a format you can read, and  
they tell us whether mail has been opened. We may use this information to  
reduce or eliminate messages sent to readers.

**Do we disclose any information to outside parties?**

We are not in the business of selling your important information to others  
and so we won’t do so. At times we may make certain personal information  
available to strategic partners that work with us to provide products,  
services, advice or that help us market to our readers. Personal  
information will only be shared by us to provide or improve our products,  
services, notices, announcements and advertising; it will not be shared with  
third parties for their marketing purposes. We do not sell, trade, or  
otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable  
information. However, this does not include trusted third parties who assist  
us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so  
long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential pursuant to  
this Privacy Policy.

**Who else might we disclose your information to?**

We may also release your information when we believe release is  
appropriate to enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights,  
property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information  
may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

It may be necessary − by law, legal process, litigation, and/or requests from  
public and governmental authorities within or outside your country of  
residence − for us to disclose your personal information. We may also  
disclose information about you if we determine that for purposes of national  
security, law enforcement, or other issues of public importance, disclosure  
is necessary or appropriate, to protect the rights, property, or safety of our  
users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other  
companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.  
Obviously, however, this does not include selling, renting, sharing, or  
otherwise disclosing personally identifiable information from you for  
commercial purposes in violation of the commitments set forth in this  
Privacy Notice.

We may also disclose information about you if we determine that disclosure  
is reasonably necessary to enforce our terms and conditions or protect our  
operations or users. Additionally, in the event of a reorganization, merger,  
or sale we may transfer any and all personal information we collect to the  
relevant third party.

**Third party links**

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products  
or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and  
independent privacy policies and you should review those when applicable.  
We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities  
of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our  
site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

**Protection of Personal Information**

We take precautions — including administrative, technical, and physical  
measures — to safeguard your personal information against loss, theft, and  
misuse, as well as against unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and  
destruction.

When you use some of our services, or post on a forum, chat room, or  
social networking service, the personal information you share is visible to  
other users and can be read, collected, or used by them. You are  
responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these  
instances. For example, if you list your name and email address in a forum  
posting, that information is public. Please take care when using these  
features.

**Integrity and Retention of Personal Information**

We hope to make it easy for you to keep your personal information  
accurate, complete, and up to date. We will retain your personal  
information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this  
Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by  
law.

**Access to Personal Information**

For personal information, we make good faith efforts to provide you with  
access so you can request that we correct the data if it is inaccurate or  
delete the data if we are not required to retain it by law or for legitimate  
business purposes. We may decline to process requests that are  
unreasonably repetitive, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize  
the privacy of others, are extremely impractical, or for which access is not  
otherwise required by local law. Access, correction, or deletion requests  
can be made through the following link:  

**California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance**

We value your privacy, and so if you are located in California, we have  
taken the necessary precautions to be in compliance with the California  
Online Privacy Protection Act. We therefore will not distribute your personal  
information to outside parties pursuant to those regulations without your  
consent.

**Children under 13 and 18**

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Childrens’ Online  
Privacy Protection Act). We do not knowingly collect personal information  
from children under 13. If we learn that we have collected the personal  
information of a child under 13 years of age we will take steps to  
immediately delete the information as soon as possible. If we sell products  
and if you are under 18, you may use our site and order these products  
only with the involvement of a parent or guardian. If we discover that you  
are under 18 years of age and are not using the site and ordering with the  
express involvement and consent of a parent or guardian, we will  
immediately cease fulfilling your order and your money will be returned.

**Our Companywide Commitment to Your Privacy**

To make sure your personal information is secure, we communicate our  
privacy and security guidelines to our employees and strictly enforce  
privacy safeguards within the company.

**Privacy Questions and Contacting us**

If you have any questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy or data  
processing, please contact us at  

**Online Privacy Policy Only**

This online Privacy Policy applies only to information collected through our  
website and not to information collected offline.

**Your Consent**  
By using our site, you consent to our web site Privacy Policy and all  
additions or deletions posted by us at any time.

**Changes to our Privacy Policy**

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. When we change the  
policy in a material way, we will do our best to provide a notice which will be  
posted on our website along with the updated Privacy Policy. All changes  
will be enforceable retroactively.

One Light Productions, Inc.  
PO Box 9675  
South Laguna CA 92652  
_Last updated: February 10, 2014_
